Today. I'm going to talk about a shameful topic.
[AI] 今天我要谈一个可耻的话题。
This has happened to many of us. and it's embarrassing.
[AI] 这在我们许多人身上都发生过。这很尴尬。
but if we don't talk about it. nothing will ever change.
[AI] 但如果我们不谈论它。什么都不会改变。
It's about being hacked.
[AI] 这是关于被黑客攻击的。
Some of us have clicked on a phishing link and downloaded a computer virus.
[AI] 我们中的一些人点击了一个网络钓鱼链接并下载了一个计算机病毒。
Some of us have had our identities stolen.
[AI] 我们有些人的身份被偷了。
And those of us who are software developers
[AI] 还有我们这些软件开发人员
might have written insecure code with security bugs in it
[AI] 可能编写了不安全的代码，其中包含安全漏洞
without realizing it.
[AI] 没有意识到。
As a cybersecurity expert.
[AI] 作为一名网络安全专家。
I have worked with countless companies on improving their cybersecurity.
[AI] 我曾与无数公司合作改善他们的网络安全。
Cybersecurity experts like me have advised companies
[AI] 像我这样的网络安全专家为公司提供了建议
on good cybersecurity practices.
[AI] 关于良好的网络安全做法。
monitoring tools
[AI] 监测工具
and proper user behaviors.
[AI] 以及正确的用户行为。
But I actually see a much bigger problem that no tool can fix:
[AI] 但我实际上看到了一个更大的问题，没有工具可以解决：
the shame associated with the mistakes that we make.
[AI] 与我们所犯的错误有关的羞耻感。
We like to think of ourselves as competent and tech savvy.
[AI] 我们喜欢认为自己有能力并且精通技术。
and when we make these mistakes that can have a really bad impact
[AI] 当我们犯了这些错误，可能会产生非常坏的影响
on us and our companies --
[AI] 关于我们和我们的公司--
anything from a simple annoyance.
[AI] 从一个简单的烦恼。
to taking a lot of time to fix.
[AI] 要花很多时间来修复。
to costing us and our employers a lot of money.
[AI] 让我们和我们的雇主损失了很多钱。
Despite billions of dollars that companies spend on cybersecurity.
[AI] 尽管公司在网络安全上花费了数十亿美元。
practitioners like me see the same problems over and over again.
[AI] 像我这样的从业者一次又一次地看到同样的问题。
Let me give you some examples.
[AI] 让我举几个例子。
The 2015 hack of Ukrainian utilities
[AI] 2015年乌克兰公用事业遭到黑客攻击
that disconnected power for 225.000 customers
[AI] 这为225.000名客户切断了电源
and took months to restore back to full operations
[AI] 并花了数月时间恢复到全面运行状态
started with a phishing link.
[AI] 从网络钓鱼链接开始。
By the way. 225.000 customers is a lot more 225.000 people.
[AI] 顺便说一句225.000名客户比225.000人多得多。
Customers can be anything from an apartment building
[AI] 顾客可以是公寓楼以外的任何东西
to an industrial facility
[AI] 工业设施
to a shopping mall.
[AI] 去购物中心。
The 2017 data breach of Equifax
[AI] 2017年Equifax数据泄露事件
that exposed personally identifiable information
[AI] 这暴露了个人身份信息
of 140 million people
[AI] 1.4亿人口
and may ultimately cost Equifax something on the order of 1.4 billion dollars:
[AI] 最终可能会花费Equifax 14亿美元：
that was caused by an exploitation of a well-known vulnerability
[AI] 这是由于利用了一个众所周知的漏洞造成的
in the company's customer consumer complaint portal.
[AI] 在公司的客户投诉门户中。
Fundamentally. this is about technology and innovation.
[AI] 从根本上讲这是关于技术和创新的。
Innovation is good; it makes our lives better.
[AI] 创新是好的；它使我们的生活更美好。
Most of the modern cars we drive today are fundamentally computers on wheels.
[AI] 我们今天驾驶的大多数现代汽车基本上都是带轮子的计算机。
They tell us where to go to avoid traffic. when to take them in for maintenance
[AI] 他们告诉我们去哪里避免交通堵塞。什么时候进行保养
and then give us all kinds of modern-day conveniences.
[AI] 然后给我们各种现代便利。
Many people use connected medical devices like pacemakers
[AI] 许多人使用连接的医疗设备，如心脏起搏器
and glucose monitors with insulin pumps.
[AI] 和带有胰岛素泵的血糖监测仪。
These devices make these people's lives better
[AI] 这些设备使这些人的生活变得更好
and sometimes even extend their lives.
[AI] 有时甚至延长他们的生命。
But anything that can be interconnected can be hacked when it's connected.
[AI] 但是任何可以相互连接的东西在连接时都可能被黑客攻击。
Did you know that the former US Vice President Dick Cheney
[AI] 你知道美国前副总统迪克·切尼
kept his pacemaker disconnected from Wi-Fi before he received a heart transplant?
[AI] 在他接受心脏移植之前，让他的起搏器与Wi-Fi断开？
I will let you figure out why.
[AI] 我会让你找出原因的。
In a digitally interconnected world. cyber risks are literally everywhere.
[AI] 在一个数字互联的世界里。网络风险无处不在。
For years. my colleagues and I have been talking about
[AI] 多年来。我的同事和我一直在谈论
this elusive notion of cybersecurity culture.
[AI] 网络安全文化这一难以捉摸的概念。
Cybersecurity culture is when everybody in the organization
[AI] 网络安全文化是指组织中的每个人
believes that cybersecurity is their job.
[AI] 相信网络安全是他们的工作。
knows what to do and what not to do
[AI] 知道该做什么和不该做什么
and does the right thing.
[AI] 做正确的事。
Unfortunately. I can't tell you which companies do this well.
[AI] 不幸地我不能告诉你哪些公司做得好。
because by doing so. I would put a juicy target on their backs
[AI] 因为这样做。我会把一个有趣的目标放在他们的背上
for ambitious attackers.
[AI] 对于雄心勃勃的攻击者。
But what I can do is make cybersecurity less mysterious.
[AI] 但我能做的是让网络安全不再那么神秘。
bring it out into the open and talk about it.
[AI] 把它公开出来，并谈论它。
There should be no mystery or secrecy within an organization.
[AI] 一个组织内部不应该有神秘或秘密。
When something is invisible and it's working.
[AI] 当某些东西是看不见的，并且它在工作时。
we don't know that it's there until it's not there.
[AI] 直到它不在那里，我们才知道它在那里。
Kind of like toilet paper.
[AI] 有点像卫生纸。
When the COVID-19 pandemic began.
[AI] 2019冠状病毒疾病流行的开始。
what has been there all of a sudden became super important
[AI] 那里发生的一切突然变得非常重要
because we couldn't find it anywhere.
[AI] 因为我们到处都找不到。
Cybersecurity is just like that:
[AI] 网络安全就是这样：
when it's working. we don't know. and we don't care.
[AI] 当它工作时。我们不知道。我们不在乎。
But when it's not working.
[AI] 但当它不起作用的时候。
it can be really. really bad.
[AI] 这可能是真的。真糟糕。
Toilet paper is pretty straightforward.
[AI] 卫生纸很简单。
Cybersecurity is mysterious and complex.
[AI] 网络安全是神秘而复杂的。
And I actually think it starts with the notion of psychological safety.
[AI] 我认为这是从心理安全的概念开始的。
This notion was popularized by an organizational behavior scientist.
[AI] 一位组织行为科学家推广了这一概念。
Amy Edmondson.
[AI] 艾米·爱德蒙森。
Amy studied behavior of medical teams in high-stakes situations like hospitals.
[AI] 艾米研究了医疗团队在医院等高风险情况下的行为。
where mistakes could be fatal.
[AI] 错误可能是致命的。
And she found out that nurses were not comfortable
[AI] 她发现护士们不舒服
bringing up suggestions to the doctors
[AI] 向医生提出建议
because of the fear of questioning authority.
[AI] 因为害怕质疑权威。
Amy helped improve medical teams
[AI] 艾米帮助改进了医疗队
to make nurses more comfortable bringing up suggestions to the doctors
[AI] 让护士更容易向医生提出建议
for patient treatment
[AI] 病人治疗
without the fear of being scolded or demeaned.
[AI] 没有被责骂或贬低的恐惧。
For that to happen. doctors needed to listen and be receptive --
[AI] 让这一切发生。医生需要倾听和接受--
without judging.
[AI] 不加评判。
Psychological safety is when everybody is comfortable speaking up
[AI] 心理安全是指每个人都能轻松地说出自己的想法
and pointing things out.
[AI] 并指出问题所在。
I want cybersecurity to be the same.
[AI] 我希望网络安全也一样。
And I want cybersecurity practitioners to be comfortable bringing suggestions up
[AI] 我希望网络安全从业人员能够轻松地提出建议
to senior executives or software developers.
[AI] 给高级管理人员或软件开发人员。
without being dismissed as those people who continue to talk about
[AI] 没有被解雇的那些人继续谈论
horrors and errors.
[AI] 恐怖和错误。
and say no.
[AI] 说不。
Not doing so is really hard
[AI] 不这样做真的很难
for the individuals who are responsible for the creation of digital products
[AI] 对于负责数字产品创作的个人
because fundamentally. it's about their pride and joy in their creations.
[AI] 因为从根本上来说。这是关于他们在创作中的骄傲和喜悦。
I once tried talking to a senior software development executive
[AI] 我曾经试着和一位高级软件开发主管交谈
about the need to do better security.
[AI] 关于需要做更好的安全性。
You know what he said?
[AI] 你知道他说了什么吗？
"Are you telling me we're developing insecure code?"
[AI] “你是说我们正在开发不安全的代码吗？”
In other words. what he heard was. "Your baby is ugly."
[AI] 换句话说。他听到的是。“你的孩子很丑。”
What if instead of focusing on what not to do.
[AI] 如果不是专注于不该做的事情，那该怎么办呢。
we focused on what to do?
[AI] 我们专注于做什么？
Like. how do we develop better software
[AI] 喜欢我们如何开发更好的软件
and protect our customer information at the same time?
[AI] 同时保护我们的客户信息？
Or how do we make sure that our organization is able to operate
[AI] 或者我们如何确保我们的组织能够运作
in crisis. under attack or in an emergency?
[AI] 在危机中。受到攻击还是处于紧急状态？
And what if we reward good things that people do in cybersecurity in some way
[AI] 如果我们以某种方式奖励人们在网络安全方面所做的好事呢
and encourage them to do so.
[AI] 并鼓励他们这样做。
like reporting security incidents.
[AI] 比如报告安全事件。
reporting potential phishing emails.
[AI] 报告潜在的网络钓鱼电子邮件。
or finding and fixing software security bugs
[AI] 或者查找和修复软件安全漏洞
in the software that they develop?
[AI] 在他们开发的软件中？
And what if we tied these good security actions to performance evaluations
[AI] 如果我们将这些良好的安全措施与性能评估联系起来呢
to make it really matter?
[AI] 让它变得真正重要？
I would love for us to communicate these good cybersecurity things
[AI] 我希望我们能交流这些良好的网络安全问题
and encourage them in some sort of company-wide communications
[AI] 并鼓励他们在公司范围内进行某种形式的沟通
like newsletters. blogs. websites. microsites --
[AI] 我喜欢时事通讯。博客。网站。微晶--
whatever we use to communicate to our organization.
[AI] 无论我们用什么来与我们的组织沟通。
What if a company announced a competition for who finds the most security bugs
[AI] 如果一家公司宣布竞争谁发现了最多的安全漏洞呢
and fixes them in a two-week development sprint
[AI] 并在为期两周的开发冲刺中修复了它们
and then announces the winner of the competition for the quarter
[AI] 然后宣布本季度比赛的获胜者
at a large company virtual town hall.
[AI] 在一家大公司的虚拟市政厅。
and then rewards these people. these winners. with something meaningful.
[AI] 然后奖励这些人。这些获胜者。有意义的东西。
like a week's vacation or a bonus.
[AI] 比如一周的假期或者奖金。
Others will see the celebration and recognition.
[AI] 其他人将看到庆祝和认可。
and they'll want to do the same.
[AI] 他们也会这么做。
In the energy industry.
[AI] 在能源行业。
there is a really strong culture of safety.
[AI] 有一种非常强大的安全文化。
People care about this culture. are proud of it.
[AI] 人们关心这种文化。我们为此感到自豪。
and there is a collective reinforcement of this culture
[AI] 这种文化得到了集体的强化
to make sure that nobody gets hurt.
[AI] 确保没有人受伤。
One of the ways they exhibit and keep this safety conscious culture going
[AI] 他们展示和保持这种安全意识文化的方式之一
is by counting and visibly displaying days since the last safety incident.
[AI] 通过计算和明显显示自上次安全事件以来的天数。
And then everybody works really hard not to have that count go back to zero
[AI] 然后每个人都努力工作，不让计数回到零
because that means that somebody did get hurt.
[AI] 因为那意味着有人受伤了。
Cybersecurity is the same as safety.
[AI] 网络安全与安全是一样的。
What if we all agree
[AI] 如果我们都同意呢
to keep that count of days since the last cybersecurity incident
[AI] 从上次网络安全事件开始算起的日子
going on forever
[AI] 永远持续下去
and then work really hard not to have it reset to zero?
[AI] 然后努力工作不让它归零？
And then certain things are a no-no.
[AI] 然后某些事情是不允许的。
and we need to clearly communicate to our organizations what they are
[AI] 我们需要清楚地向我们的组织传达他们是什么
in an easily digestible and maybe even fun way.
[AI] 以一种易于消化甚至有趣的方式。
like gamification or simulations.
[AI] 比如游戏化或者模拟。
to make sure that people can remember this.
[AI] 以确保人们能够记住这一点。
And if somebody does something they're not supposed to do.
[AI] 如果有人做了不该做的事。
they should face some sort of consequences.
[AI] 他们应该面临某种后果。
So. for example. if an employee buys equipment on Amazon or eBay
[AI] 所以例如如果员工在亚马逊或易趣上购买设备
or uses personal Dropbox for their company business.
[AI] 或者在公司业务中使用个人Dropbox。
then they should face some sort of consequences.
[AI] 那么他们应该面临某种后果。
And when this happens. executives should get the same treatment
[AI] 当这种情况发生时。高管们应该得到同样的待遇
as regular employees.
[AI] 作为正式雇员。
because if they don't. then people won't believe that it's real
[AI] 因为如果他们不相信，人们就不会相信这是真的
and will go back to their old behaviors.
[AI] 并将回到他们以前的行为。
It's OK to talk about mistakes.
[AI] 谈论错误是可以的。
but just like a teenager who violates the rules tells us about it.
[AI] 但就像一个违反规则的青少年告诉我们的一样。
we appreciate that they told us about it.
[AI] 我们感谢他们告诉我们这件事。
but there should still be some sort of consequences.
[AI] 但仍有一些后果。
Cybersecurity is a journey.
[AI] 网络安全是一段旅程。
It's not a destination.
[AI] 这不是目的地。
and we need to keep working on it.
[AI] 我们需要继续努力。
I would love for us to celebrate cybersecurity people
[AI] 我希望我们能为网络安全人士庆祝
like the heroes that they are.
[AI] 就像他们是英雄一样。
If we think about it. they are firefighters.
[AI] 如果我们仔细想想。他们是消防员。
emergency room doctors and nurses.
[AI] 急诊室的医生和护士。
law enforcement. risk executives and business strategists
[AI] 执法。风险主管和业务策略师
all in the same persona.
[AI] 都在同一个角色中。
And they help us protect our modern life that we like so much.
[AI] 它们帮助我们保护我们非常喜欢的现代生活。
They protect our identities. our inventions. our intellectual property.
[AI] 他们保护我们的身份。我们的发明。我们的知识产权。
our electric grid. medical devices.
[AI] 我们的电网。医疗设备。
connected cars and myriad other things.
[AI] 连接的汽车和无数其他东西。
And I'd like to be on that team.
[AI] 我想加入这个团队。
So let's agree that this thing is with us to stay.
[AI] 所以，让我们同意，这件事是与我们留在一起。
let's create a safe environment to learn from our mistakes.
[AI] 让我们创造一个安全的环境，从错误中吸取教训。
and let's commit to making things better.
[AI] 让我们致力于让事情变得更好。
Thank you.
[AI] 非常感谢。